My name is Elena Gilbert.
I'm a new vampire, and there
have been complications.
I know that I'm sired
to you, Damon.
You know what would
make me happy?
That what you actually felt for me
was real.
But there's hope
now there's a cure.
This cure has ruined us, and it
hasn't even been found yet.
What do you know
about Silas?
He's the world's first
immortal being,
who just happens
to be the person with the cure.
Unlikely alliances
have formed.
What the hell
are you doing here?
How can I help?
No feelings.
No attachment.
To make sure we
never find the cure.
You're going to find
Jeremy Gilbert,
and you're going to
kill him.
Our only
chance is to risk everything.
Kol compelled Damon
to kill you.
You're gonna kill
Kol instead.
♪The Vampire Diaries 4x12 ♪
A View to a Kill
Original Air Date on January 31, 2013
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
I don't appreciate you
invading my privacy
like some kind of
creeping Tom.
Well, I apologize
for breaking up
this sordid little tryst,
but I do have some
urgent business.
Or have you forgotten
that our paranoid brother Kol
is running around
with a white oak stake
and homicide on
the brain?
He tried to kill me last night.
I didn't forget.
Yes. Well,
unfortunately,
he seems to have absconded with my
set of daggers.
Oh, poor Nik. However will you
get your way
without your
precious daggers?
They were so handy when you
wanted to end a conversation
with one of us.
Kol's irrational
fear of Silas
has pushed him
off the edge.
We need to put him down before
he does any more damage.
Now, I know you have
the last dagger,
and I know you have
some white ash, so hand it over.
Hmm. And leave myself
unprotected?
You can file that request
under "no chance in hell."
Be gone by the time
I've showered.
Lurkers aren't
welcome here.
I need that dagger, Stefan.
Talk some sense
into her.
Why don't you
talk some sense into her?
I'm headed home to play
prison guard to Damon.
He's on lockdown
ever since Kol compelled him
to kill Jeremy
last night.
You see? That's
my point exactly.
If you let Kol
run free,
then Jeremy won't live to see
his junior prom,
and we can kiss
our map to the cure good-bye.
But if you help me
dagger Kol,
Damon will be
uncompelled,
Jeremy will live, and we'll all be
on our merry way
to a human Elena.
Where are you?
I told Caroline
I'd take her place
at decade dance prep,
but none of the rest of you showed.
I know. I'm sorry.
I had to, though.
I've got Jeremy
under house arrest
because Kol wants
to kill him.
And Klaus
wants to take him
on some vampire-slaying
road trip.
And since neither
of them were invited in,
it's the only place
that I can keep him safe.
Why does it sound like
you're under fire?
Apparently I'm living
in a fraternity house now.
I'm training.
Me, too.
Train yourself to
do some dishes.
And put these
weapons away
before someone tries to
use one on me.
Well, it's hard for me to
look forward to this dance
while you're trapped
in your house.
Listen, I have a plan
to put an end to all of this.
I want Jeremy
to kill Kol.
You want him to kill
an original?
Think about it.
Kol's sire line must
stretch to the moon by now.
If Jeremy kills Kol, every vampire
that he's ever turned,
not to mention everyone that
they've turned, will die,
which means the Hunter's mark
will be complete,
and we'll have our key
to finding the cure.
I'm on my way.
We'll figure it out.
Do you think Caroline
will notice
if there's only 89
red balloons?
Actually, probably yes.
Aah!
What happened?
I don't know.
There's something
in the water.
Are you serious?
You dumped vervain
into the water supply?
Where did you even
get it?
I have my sources.
I'm also reinstating
the curfew
and canceling
all town events.
Dad, there's
the dance tonight.
Not anymore.
Are you serious?
Honey, I'm trying
to protect you, not punish you.
The well-being
of this town is my job now.
No. Dad, it's mine,
and I've been doing fine
without you getting
involved.
You've been doing fine?
Would you like me
to read you all the names
of the people that have
gone missing
or died in tragic accidents
in your senior year alone?
Head straight home,
please.
We're having
a family meeting.
No one can get
to the cure
if you're too dead
to find it.
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Aah! Aah! Aah! Aah!
Gonna snap my neck again?
Because I woke up
feeling completely unmurderous,
and I'm pretty sure
that it's safe to set me free.
You practically
bled me dry.
At least spring for
a bag or something.
I'm thirsty.
Not exactly what I had in mind.
Uh. Uh.
Hello mate.
What the hell
are you doing here?
Babysitting.
Oh.
Give him a vial of blood
every couple of hours
so he doesn't desiccate.
If he gets too much
strength back
or if he just
annoys you,
bleed him out again.
Is that your best shot?
He's still pissed at me
for sleeping with Elena.
Are you sure
about that?
Because I caught him
trying to sneak out
of Rebekah's bed
this morning,
which would suggest
to me that he's moved on.
Well, well. Looks
like my brother
ripped out a page
of my revenge sex handbook.
Well, why don't you two
enjoy your little, uh,
villain bonding time?
I'll let you know when I get
the dagger from Rebekah.
Damon's fine.
With all the creature
comforts he deserves.
That's not
why I called.
Kol just tried
to kill Bonnie.
What? Is she ok?
Yeah, just
shaken up.
She managed to
hold him off,
but Kol seems
pretty intent
on murdering anyone who's looking
for that cure.
Yeah. Klaus has me
trying to convince Rebekah
to give up her dagger
so we can take care of Kol.
I don't want to
just dagger Kol.
I want Jeremy
to kill him.
What did you
just say?
Bonnie says she's got
all this crazy new power.
She thinks she can
hold him long enough
for Jeremy to get
a clean shot.
And then what, huh?
Klaus and Rebekah
will kill every single one of us
out of spite.
They may be
dysfunctional, bickering lunatics,
but they stick
together no matter what.
That's why you need
to find the dagger
and use it on Rebekah.
She can't come looking
for revenge
if she's lying in a box.
I know you can't because
vampires can't use the dagger,
but Matt can.
It's not like she
doesn't deserve it.
And Bonnie thinks that she can
get Klaus out of the picture, too,
at least temporarily.
Once we get this cure,
none of this will matter
because we can use it
against them.
All right, fine,
but how do you plan to lure Kol in?
Jeremy Gilbert.
Nice to see I'm still
on your speed dial, mate.
Hey, you want to meet up
at the batting cages in Denver?
Actually,
it's Elena Gilbert.
What a treat.
Yeah, I was just
thinking of all the clever ways
I could have
your brother killed,
but I'd settle
for ripping off
his illustrated arm
instead.
I need to talk
to you--in person.
I want to call
a truce in the name of Silas.
I'll meet you
wherever you want.
I'll come to you.
I'll tell you what.
How about
I come to you?
Open the door
and invite me in.
I'm waiting.
Let me in, and let's
talk truce.
Hello?
Wouldn't it be kind of
stupid to invite you in?
On the contrary.
I can't kill your brother with
my own two hands,
or I'll suffer
the hunter's curse
and spend the next
20 years trying to off myself
in gruesome ways.
And I've heard that vervain's
back in town,
so I can't compel you
to kill him either.
So I think it's fair to say
you're semi-safe,
for now.
He's the only one who can
invite him inside.
He's right,
obviously.
You'd think being
alive for over 1,000 years
would teach me
some manners,
but I couldn't
resist stopping by.
If I let you in,
my brother goes.
You're not
getting near him.
Fair enough.
You can come in.
No gold medal for bravery,
I see.
Another thing I love
about the modern age
is music anytime
you like.
So, is the part
where you offer
me a drink
so we can have
a proper chat.
The colors, the fabric,
the eighties
were just tragic.
You know, I think
shoulder pads
rival 17th-century Puritan
smocks for crimes against fashion.
Looking for something
to wear to the dance?
Aye. Are you
asking me to a date?
Actually,
it was canceled.
So why are you here?
Back for more
dagger talk?
Somebody has
some trust issues.
It's called
a healthy skepticism.
I know you were trying
to sneak out this morning.
I'm not stupid.
Sorry.
I'm still trying
to get used to this.
Do you regret it?
No.
Do you want it
to happen again?
Maybe.
Even if I don't
give you the dagger?
You think that
I would sleep with you
just to get
the dagger?
Don't give me
that innocent look.
You've done
plenty to me
in the name of
getting what you want.
Well, I guess I should pack up
these racks.
Just another
failed attempt
at getting to
a high-school dance.
Why do you care so much
about a high school dance?
I don't.
I was just bored.
Right.
Well, we can still go.
If you want?
Not if it's
canceled, we can't.
Since when do you
care about the rules?
You know, none of this
would be an issue
if you'd have just
done your job properly.
I was perfectly
willing to let you train Jeremy.
No, you weren't.
Are you kidding?
You got there
on day two.
Do you know how
hard it is to get
these X-Box brains
to focus?
And then when I turned
a room full of barflies
into vampires
for him to slaughter,
you let Kol kill them.
Your brother problem,
not mine, buddy.
And whose bright idea
was it
to saddle Jeremy
with a conscience, hmm?
Well, we couldn't
have him trying to stake Elena
in her sleep,
now, could we?
Ah, yes, for
the love of Elena.
How is it that she manages
to overlook
every horrific thing
you've ever done?
Is it willful
ignorance
or perhaps something
more pathological?
Some people
are just more capable
of forgiveness than others.
Bet you score about a negative 500
in that realm.
Come on. There
must be a secret.
It can't just be the sire bond.
What is it?
Compulsion?
Manipulation?
What is it you say to her?
I think this has
something to do
with a certain
blond vampire.
I think you murdered
Carol Lockwood,
and I think
you're worried
that Caroline's never
going to forgive you.
You've done worse.
Debatable. See,
I don't mind being the bad guy,
because somebody has to fill
that role and get things done.
You do bad things
for no reason.
You do them
to be a dick.
Debatable.
If you're gonna be bad,
be bad with purpose.
Otherwise you're just
not worth forgiving.
Sorry, I have to take up
the old people alcohol.
Yeah, that's the problem
with people today.
They have no
drinking imagination.
Turn-of-the-century
New Orleans--
now, they knew
how to make a drink.
You lived
in New Orleans?
We all did,
till Niklaus shoved
a dagger in my heart.
Why? What did you do?
What makes you think
I did anything?
Has your alliance
with my brother
softened you
to his horrors?
I don't have
an alliance with Klaus.
We had a mutual interest
in finding the cure.
That's all.
Had?
Yes.
And I'm willing to
give up looking for it
if you promise to
leave my brother alone.
Now can you teach me
how to make this?
I'll get some ice.
Bonnie where are you,
I've called, like,
17 times.
Kol is in our house.
We need you.
Ok, I'm headed
to your house now.
Would you like one?
Sure. Why not?
You're really good at that game.
Especially considering
you've been locked up in a coffin
for a hundred years.
I'm a quick learner.
Speedy reflexes.
It's not much like the
real thing, though, is it?
You have killed, haven't you?
Or are you one of those
Mary Sue vampires?
I killed...once.
I'm guessing your number is
a lot higher than mine.
You lose track over the years.
So are we going
to talk about Silas
or just jibber jabber?
No one else seems
to think Silas exists.
So why do you?
I used to run with some witches
in Africa in the 14th century,
Haiti in the 17th century,
New Orleans in the 1900s.
They all knew about Silas
and that he needed to stay buried.
I actually hold witches
in high esteem.
Yeah, but why Silas?
Why are you so afraid of him?
They said if Silas rises,
he'll unleash hell on earth.
I happen to like earth just the way it is.
That's pretty Biblical.
Well, that's the other
problem with people today.
They've lost faith,
and in that loss, they no longer
know who they should fear.
I have to get to Elena.
Have you seen my phone?
I've got your phone, and
I've got your car keys.
And I told you we are
having a family meeting.
Is that something you read in a book?
Because we have never had a family meeting.
I've let this go on long enough.
Shane said you and your magic
are like a ticking time bomb.
And I told you he's crazy.
I lost your mother to witchcraft.
I don't intend to lose you.
It's not your life. It's mine.
Hey, is Bonnie here?
She's busy.
It's important.
What's going on?
I've called you, like, a hundred times.
Kol is in our house.
- I have to go. - I said no.
Stop telling me what to do!
No one's going anywhere!
Mom?
Abby, please come in.
What are you doing here?
Your father called. Who's Professor Shane?
What has he been teaching you?
Bonnie, we don't have time for this.
This is a family matter.
My sister's in trouble.
We need Bonnie's help.
My daughter is done
helping Elena Gilbert.
- Now get out. - Mom!
Answer my question.
What lies has this professor
been telling you?
Don't! Jeremy!
Hey, stop!
Stop.
Don't hurt her.
She's my mom.
Look at me.
Just go, Okay?
I'm right behind you.
You wanna talk?
Let's talk.
But I think this is a good year.
What if I said
I don't believe you?
Ok, you got me. I don't know
anything about wine.
Just seems odd that
you being so willing
to give up something
you want so much.
I would do anything
for my brother.
And if what you're saying
about Silas is true.
What does it matter what I want
if it puts everyone else
in danger?
Well, this has been a enlightening.
Thanks for the drinks.
I'll take your request
for truth under advisement.
Is there any chance that
you can be wrong about Silas?
Trust me, Elena.
Some things are better left buried.
Think I saw a horror movie
that started just like this.
Did you know they play movies
on TV all night long now?
Hundreds of them.
So much better than those silly
black-and-white picture
shows we use to go to.
I don't know.
Kind of miss the old ones.
You got any requests for the DJ?
I'll let you pick. Nothing cheesy.
Oh, that leaves out about half the decade.
- Hope you like the cure. - Funny.
So is everything
about the eighties so...
excessive?
I think, it had its charm.
"Say anything"--
Lloyd Dobler standing outside
of a bedroom window
with a boombox over his head
desperately trying to get back
the girl of his dreams.
"Princess Bride"--
Wesley slays giant rats for love.
"Breakfast Club"-- one detention
turns a bunch of outcasts into allies.
So it was a decade of
sentimental drivel, as well.
Well, I was gonna
say love, friendship,
Possibility of anything happening.
You would've loved it.
And why is that?
Because, as much as we
both hate to admit it,
we care about those things.
That better not be a corsage.
I loathe corsages.
These were all the rage in the eighties.
Let's dance.
I'm sorry. He left.
I mean, I tried to stall
as long as I could.
That's Bonnie. She was right behind me.
I've considered
your request for truce.
Request denied.
I'm sorry. I've already
been invited in.
Hide and seek?
Fine by me.
Dad needs to mind
his own business,
he had no right to call you here.
It's not just your father, Bonnie.
Witches talk. Word gets around.
I found a new way to practice.
It's unconventional,
but I can handle myself, I promise.
That's not what Shane said.
Shane is sitting
in a jail cell right now.
You're gonna take
his word over mine?
I've warned you
about dark magic before.
It's not dark magic.
It's expression, and I need it.
They found a cure, Mom.
There's a cure for vampirism,
and I can
do the spell to access it.
I can save you,
but I have to go...
Now.
I'm not the one
that needs to be saved.
You are.
Your brother's lack of
communication is infuriating.
It's one of his trademarks,
like his brooding and his hair.
I don't understand
what's taking so long.
I mean, how hard is it
to steal a dagger?
From the vampire
who's been stabbed by it
as many times as your sister,
I'd say difficult.
Sweet.
You disappoint me, Damon.
You're not trying very hard
to get out of here.
I expected more the daring escape artist,
less the cell potato.
Well, I am compelled to kill Jeremy,
so I figured it's probably smarter
to sit in there
and chitchat with you
than try to bust out of here
like the Hulk.
How do you think Elena
felt about that, by the way.
Your inability to overcome
Kol's compulsion for a single moment,
even though it meant
killing the person
she loves the most in the world?
She's met me.
She knows impulse control
is not my strong suit.
Still, must be hard
trying to live up to Stefan.
I remember when I compelled
him to feed on Elena,
he fought so hard,
he actually managed to resist.
Now, that's love.
What do you know about love?
I know that you're
in love with Elena,
but I think you're afraid
of what might happen
when we find the cure
at the end of the rainbow.
Personally, I don't see
a fairy-tale ending for you?
All I see is Stefan and Elena.
I think you see the same thing.
Well, if it isn't the
happy homicidal maniac.
Do you know that your
darling former blood bag
and her brother
are trying to kill me?
What?
Don't pretend like
you're not in on it.
Your obsession to find the cure
clearly trumps any sibling
loyalty you once felt.
I don't know what you're talking about.
I'm going to rip off Jeremy's arm
and kill Elena just for sport.
Then I'm coming for you.
What the hell is going on?
I don't know.
What are Stefan
and Elena planning?
I don't know.
I've been stuck in the penalty box
with you since yesterday.
Stefan won't talk to me,
And Elena won't come to see me.
So maybe you're right.
Maybe she's written me off.
Tell me what you know.
I don't know anything about a plan.
You stay here till I return.
I will stay here until you return...
or not.
It's amazing which you can find
stashed away in the teachers' lounge.
This song is not as terrible
as the other ones.
This song is the Godfather
of rock anthems, ok?
What's going on with you?
You're... fun tonight.
I can't listen to this music
without thinking of my best friend Lexi.
We spent most of the eighties together.
I remember this one time
she snuck us backstage
and compelled half the band
to do tequila shots
with us before the show.
She was fearless, kind of like you.
So you slept with her, too?
No. It wasn't like that.
I was just a better person
when I was with her.
I didn't think
I'd ever feel that way again.
Until Elena.
And now that's over.
That look right there,
that is why I don't let myself care.
Well, you can say that,
But we both know
it's not true.
Don't worry.
I'll protect you if Kol tracks his way
to this abandoned dance.
I think I'll choose next song.
No. You know what?
I've a better idea.
That way.
Will, you coming?
Uh!
Missed.
Go!
Aah! Uh!
Now, About that arm.
Like that!
This is ridiculous.
Well, that's the whole point
of the "Breakfast Club" slide.
It's supposed to be ridiculous.
No. That's--
That's cheating.
What is fun about hurtling down a hallway
like a teenage imbecile?
You're just gonna have
to do it to find out.
All right. It's the shoes.
Take off your shoes, you'll be fine, ok?
This is what you want right?
Go ahead.
Take care.
You're right, I do care.
I want stupid koala corsages
and a prom.
I want to have kids with someone
who loves me enough to stand
outside my window with a stupid boombox.
I want to be human.
So let Klaus put down my brother.
Let's go find the cure.
Come on, let's go.
You dragged her?
Just enough to keep her down
until I can get some witches here
to clean her mind from that poison
that professor has been teaching her.
That's not happening.
Bonnie, please.
Aah! Oh!
Bonnie--
I don't belong to
the spirits anymore.
I belong to myself. Sorry.
Now, like I said, I don't
fancy the hunter's curse.
So I'm just gonna chop off
your arm, but don't worry.
I'll heal you right up with
a bit of blood after.
Sorry about the sting.
Now, which arm is it? Is it left or right?
I'll just chop off both to be safe.
Jeremy! Now!
What did you do?
We didn't have a choice.
He was trying to cut off Jeremy's arm.
Lies.
He never would've gotten
inside if you hadn't have
set a trap for him.
You said you were gonna
put him down, too.
I was gonna make him
suffer on my terms!
I want to burn this house
to the ground,
and then when you try
to flee for your lives,
I'll kill you both without blinking.
You kill us, you'll never
get to the cure.
You'll never be able to make
any more hybrids.
You really think I care for an instant
about my bloody hybrids?
I want the cure so I can destroy it.
I would've killed you all
the second we dug it up,
but now I'm just gonna watch
you burn instead.
Invite him in.
Do it.
Come in.
Living room. Go.
Witch, you can't do this to me.
You have no idea what I can do now.
I will hunt all of you
to your end!
Do you hear me? Do you?
I don't believe you.
Kol is not dead. He can't be.
Listen, Rebekah.
They didn't have a choice.
Kol started this when
he went after Jeremy.
He went after you, too.
Do you remember?
I mean, he was never gonna
let us find the cure.
So you knew.
This whole night, you knew.
I'm not gonna let the people
that I care about get hurt.
Not Jeremy, not Elena,
not even Damon.
And you can hate me for it.
Now he can't hurt you, either.
And I want us to find
this cure together,
you and me.
Not just for Elena, but for you.
So you can have what you want.
You can be who you want.
You can be human again.
Everyone deserves
a second chance right?
Why would I trust you?
I don't know.
I guess I could give you my word,
but at the end of the day
you'll just have to take a leap.
Didn't work.
It took time for
Finn's line to die off.
Remember? It'll work.
What if it doesn't?
Where's that Gilbert optimism?
Sorry I missed all the excitement.
I'm just happy to see you.
So I guess I didn't miss much.
Got the Silas's headstone.
We're just waiting for
Jeremy's mark to grow.
- Klaus is trapped in our living room.
- Temporarily.
I drawn the new moon
to bind the spell.
Got three days to find
that cure, four max.
If we don't, we might as well
look up Katherine Pierce
and see if she wants
some company in hiding.
'cuz he will come after us.
We'll find it.
Now we've got Rebekah taken care of,
all we need is Professor Shane,
and we'll have
everything we need.
Yeah, I didn't uh...I didn't dagger her.
What? Why not?
I didn't need to, she's on our side.
On our side?
Did you really just say that?
Yeah. She handed
over the headstone,
I mean she wants to find this cure
more than anyone of us.
Why would you possibly think
that you could trust her?
Let me guess. She pledged her allegiance
to you while you were naked in the sack.
I bet you're just dying to get
that out, Weren't you Damon?
Oh was this supposed to be secret?
Maybe you should make that a little clearer
while you're bleeding me dry in our cellar.
Yeah. To keep you
from killing Jeremy.
Stop it, both of you.
Now why don't you tell her
to calm down, Damon?
You've managed to use that sire bond
pretty well so far, haven't you?
It's happening.
My God.
What? You can see it?
Here we go.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org