Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
- You didn't say there'd be such security.
- They moved the flight forward.
We'll have to go ahead
as planned anyway.
Toro? Sounds like a load of bull.
James.
Be careful.
Well, small world. You're a Toro, too.
I'll see you in Miami.
Fill her up.
EAST BERLIN
Your guests have arrived, Ambassador.
We should go, my dear.
Well...
You become more beautiful every day.
- I'm over here.
- Of course you are.
This is Miss Penelope Smallbone,
my new assistant.
Miss Smallbone.
What can I say, Moneypenny? Except that
she is as attractive and as charming...
- As I used to be?
- I didn't say that.
You're such a flatterer, James.
Moneypenny, you know there never has
been and never will be anybody but you.
So you've told me.
- Welcome to Universal Exports.
- Take it, dear.
- That's all you'll ever get from him.
- Thank you, Commander Bond.
- Do you know me?
- Miss Moneypenny described you.
In nauseating detail.
Really?
I can see you're going
to fit in here very nicely.
- Good morning, 007.
- Morning, sir.
- Minister.
- Commander.
I think you know Jim Fanning,
our art expert.
- Yes. Hello, Jim.
- James.
- Do you know what this is?
- It looks like a Fabergé egg, sir.
One of the jewelled eggs by Carl Fabergé
as a gift for the Russian royal family.
They're priceless and very rare.
This one contains a model
of the imperial state coach.
- Top marks, 007.
- Thank you, sir.
Except it's a fake.
There's the real thing. It's being
auctioned at Sotheby's this afternoon.
This is the fourth egg
to turn up at auction this year.
It's from none of the usual sources.
Anonymous seller, Swiss bank account.
I'd say that the vendor was a Russian.
And now this turns up.
A near-perfect forgery.
I think Commander Bond
should accompany you to the sale.
Splendid. I could use
an extra pair of eyes.
We could try and spot the seller.
They usually turn up out of interest
or perhaps just to bump up the price.
Thank you, Fanning.
Not at all.
If it is the Russians,
it may be an effort to raise currency
for covert operations abroad
or for payoffs.
Either way,
we'd better find out what they're up to.
- Yes, Minister.
- Eyes only, 007.
Operation Trove.
You'll be replacing 009.
He turned up dead in East Germany
with that egg in his hand.
There's not much to go on.
Well, we do have one lead, Minister.
"Property of a Lady."
Next on the agenda is the continuing
mutual disarmament talks with NATO.
I assume you've all read
General Gogol's report.
It seems very thorough.
Thank you, Comrade Chairman.
I believe I express the opinion
of everyone present
that adoption of NATO proposals does
not compromise our defensive position.
- Comrade Chairman.
- General Orlov.
General Gogol is presumptuous.
He speaks for himself and others
who cling to timid, outdated
and unrealistic policies.
Must I remind you, the committee,
of our overwhelming superiority
over NATO forces
before we give it away?
In East Germany
under my direct command,
I have 31 divisions,
including 11 tank divisions
and another five in Czechoslovakia.
In support, on the Russian western
border are 60 divisions,
including 22 tank divisions.
In all, a 10-1 advantage.
American and West German forces
can field at most ten armoured divisions.
The British maintain only a token force.
We have played out a variety of attack
strategies on the new Kutuzov computer
and find that a lightning thrust by
ten armoured divisions from the north,
and by five more through Czechoslovakia,
lead to total victory in five days
against any possible defence scenario.
This is absolute madness.
We know where it will end.
NATO will counterattack
with nuclear weapons.
Never.
The West is decadent and divided.
It has no stomach
to risk our atomic reprisals.
Throughout Europe, daily demonstrations
demand unilateral nuclear disarmament.
I see no reason to risk war
to satisfy your personal paranoia
and thirst for conquest.
We must turn our energies
to pressing domestic problems.
- General Gogol, let me remind you...
- Comrades, sit down.
- I wish to tell you...
- Both of you.
World socialism
will be achieved peaceably.
Our military role is strictly defensive.
Is that understood, General Orlov?
General Gogol, would you continue?
Thank you, Comrade Chairman. I will
now turn to the specifics of my report...
Tell him I will be there
as quickly as possible.
Please. Please.
- I am trying to concentrate.
- Lenkin.
- What is it?
- It's terrible news, Comrade General.
The reproduction
has been stolen in transit.
The thief was dealt with,
but the egg was lost in the river.
Your incompetence will destroy us all.
- We'll have a replacement made.
- There is no time, Comrade General.
I have just been informed of
an unscheduled inventory in two days.
Control yourself.
I'll tell our London people
we must have the genuine egg back.
I hope we can reach them in time.
Sold to Busoni.
The next lot is number 48.
A superb green-gold
lmperial Easter egg by Carl Fabergé.
Enamelled in translucent green,
enclosed by gold laurel-leaf trellis.
Set with blue sapphires and
four petalled gold flowers with diamonds.
- How much should it fetch?
- £250-300,000. Anything more'd be crazy.
...used by Tsar Nicholas
in 1897 in Moscow.
Property of a Lady.
Well, there are quite a few ladies here.
She wouldn't have to be here in person.
She could be represented by proxy.
I'll start it at £150,000.
150, 60.
170. 170.
180, 190.
200. Against you, madam.
- Any more?
- Now there is a lady.
£220,000.
240.
James, stick to the business in hand.
£260,000.
280.
£300,000.
And 20?
Are you bidding, sir?
£320,000. New bidder.
- That's interesting.
- You know him?
Kamal Khan. Usually a seller.
Marginal quality from dubious sources.
£380,000.
- 400 in the centre.
- Well, that should do it.
- Kamal has gone over the top.
- Your bid, sir. 400,000.
400,000. Any more?
425. New bidder.
Thank you, sir.
- 425.
- Have you gone mad?
Let's see how badly he wants it.
450?
450. 475?
The bid is 450. 475?
Against you, sir. No more than 450.
- Jim?
- The bid is £450,000.
I have 475.
£500,000.
I have half a million pounds. All done?
Any more?
Yours, sir, for £500,000.
- The next lot is...
- We could have been stuck with it.
- I doubt it. He had to buy it.
- But why?
That's what I intend to find out.
You had no business bidding for that egg.
What would you have done if you'd got it?
I would have claimed it was a fake, sir,
and not paid.
Not paid?
Here's the original. I switched it
with the fake during the auction.
Good God.
And what happens
when the buyer discovers that?
Well, he complains. If he's legitimate.
- Well?
- I don't think he will complain.
According to Fanning,
this Kamal usually sells. Now he buys.
I believe that the fake will smoke him out.
Our tail followed him to Heathrow
where he caught a plane to Delhi.
You must go there, too.
I'll alert Sadruddin, our man in Station I,
to keep him under surveillance.
- Book yourself on the next flight out.
- Well, I've 55 minutes to catch it, sir.
- Oh, Bond?
- Sir?
Sign a chit for that egg before you go.
It's government property now.
Of course, sir.
Charming tune.
You do take English money?
Only gold sovereigns.
Please.
I'm Vijay.
Special expediter, Universal Exports.
- Welcome to India, Commander Bond.
- Call me James.
- Where's Sadruddin?
- Waiting in the taxi.
This was the wrong cover. I hate snakes.
Taxi. Please be comfortable.
- I am Sadruddin, Head of Section.
- How do you do?
- I booked you in at the Shivnivas Hotel.
- Good. My luggage?
Gone ahead.
What can you tell me about Kamal Khan?
Exiled Afghan prince.
Sportsman - polo, cricket, tennis.
- I play a bit myself.
- Really?
As a matter of fact, I've got
a part-time job as a pro at Kamal's club.
- What have you learned so far?
- My backhand's improved.
Kamal lives there on the hill.
The Monsoon Palace.
It's heavily guarded.
- How do I get to him?
- He plays backgammon at the hotel.
As a guest,
you're automatically a member.
- Let's meet there later.
- I'll change into something less casual.
Here, you may need this
to play with your asp.
Good morning. Name's Bond.
I believe you have a reservation.
- We've been expecting you.
- Good.
I hope you have a pleasant stay.
I'm sure I will.
Thank you.
Your luggage has been unpacked, sir.
- Oh, thank you.
- If I can be of further assistance...
- Anything at all?
- Maybe later.
- How's he doing?
- The Major's no novice.
- But Kamal has won 200,000 rupees.
- You'll have a job beating this.
I feel lucky. Shall we double?
Of course.
20,000 rupees.
- Always a double six when you need it.
- Always.
- How do you do it.
- It's all in the wrist.
- It's hopeless.
- Shall we have another game, Major?
- Same stake?
- Yes, I'll have another go.
Your luck's got to run out some time.
May I join you?
Sotheby's. Half a million pounds?
- The man at the auction.
- Precisely.
You have a good memory for faces.
And figures.
- This can't be a coincidence.
- No.
- What will you have?
- Nothing, thank you.
Some other time, perhaps?
Thank you.
Six and one.
- Well?
- Looks like the Major has got him.
Why don't we make it interesting, Major?
Double to 100,000 rupees.
I can't accept. Not with your luck.
You win.
I would have taken that double, myself.
Then why don't you take over
the Major's position? Mr...?
Bond.
James Bond. Thank you, I'd be delighted.
100,000 rupees, then.
Double six.
Not such a good double to accept,
after all, was it?
- Double.
- Of course.
You can only win with a double six.
The stake is 200,000 rupees.
Do you have the cash?
Well, I think that this
should be ample security.
Don't you?
Play, Mr Bond.
You'll need a great deal of luck
to get out of this.
Oh, luck?
Well, then I shall use player's privilege,
and use your lucky dice.
It's all in the wrist.
Double sixes.
Fancy that.
200,000 rupees.
I prefer cash.
- Get it cashed for him.
- Yes, sir.
Spend the money quickly, Mr Bond.
I intend to, Kamal Khan.
My security.
And yours?
It's not really in the wrist, you know.
- Should I be following them?
- Yes, but I think they'll be following this.
Thank you.
Vijay will take you from here.
I'll see if I can find out more about Kamal.
Good. Hold on to these, will you?
Keep you in curry
for a few weeks, won't it?
Thank you.
It's a wonderful racket, this.
- Vijay, we have company.
- No problem. This is a company car.
Step on it.
This should shake 'em off.
Thank God for hard currency.
Game, set and match. Hang on, James.
Keep your head down.
Thank you.
Get off my bed.
Here. Catch.
Excuse me.
Thank you.
You'd better stick this back yourself.
James, over here. Come on.
Vijay. The money I gave you.
Here. Rupees!
Easy come, easy go.
It pays to advertise.
This way, James.
Ah, Q.
- How are you?
- Most unhappy, 007, thanks to you.
How can I be expected
to maintain the quality of my work?
Sent out here at a moment's notice.
Have you any smaller thread?
Someone stuck a knife in my wallet.
Pity they missed you.
Karen, see to that, will you?
I've also mislaid my PPK.
- Anything else?
- No, that's all.
Blast.
Having problems keeping it up, Q?
Experimental model.
- Hello, Smithers.
- Commander.
- Smashing, Q.
- Come on. I have a few things for you.
Very nice, Smithers.
Is the homing device ready yet?
Not only a homing device, but an
extremely delicate microphone as well.
It goes in there like that.
Now, take a fountain pen.
Twist the top,
and a highly concentrated mixture
of nitric and hydrochloric acid.
- Dissolves all metals.
- Wonderful for poison-pen letters.
Pay attention, 007.
Pull the top off the pen.
With this ultrasensitive earpiece,
you can listen in on the bug.
The homing device is compatible with
the radio directional finder in your watch.
If you haven't lost it.
That's amazing, Q. It does work.
What's that?
That's the latest liquid-crystal TV.
Very handy.
Perfect image, Q.
Really, 007.
Look, I haven't time
for these adolescent antics.
- It's the best we can do.
- It's beautiful. Thank you.
Go on, get along. I've got my work to do.
- I'll give you a hand, Q.
- Thank you.
Don't forget this.
Don't let him teach you
any of his bad habits.
Mr Bond, your table is ready.
- I didn't reserve one.
- Your guest is waiting, sir.
This way, please.
Thank you.
You changed your mind.
- I'm glad.
- Are you?
Well, let's put it this way.
So far, you are the least lethal and
by far the prettiest of Kamal's friends.
Thank you.
So does he have
a proposition for me, or do you?
He suggests a trade.
The egg for your life.
I'd heard the price of eggs
was going up, but isn't that a little high?
Charge it to Room...?
Oh, 27.
Along with the champagne, I suppose?
I'll leave it at the desk.
You don't mind?
Why? Has Kamal forgotten
what I look like already?
It's for me.
So that if I depart this world suddenly,
you'll have something
to remember me by?
Something like that.
It's for my scrapbook. I collect memories.
Well, let's get on with making a few.
I need refilling.
Of course you do.
I'll get some more.
Don't bother.
We'll make yours a loving cup.
What a good idea.
Forgive my curiosity, but what is that?
That's my little octopussy.
Good morning.
Morning.
I didn't want to wake you.
But since you're up,
I can say a proper goodbye.
What is the time?
Beautiful view, isn't it?
- I don't know how to say goodbye.
- Actions speak louder than words.
So right.
In. Out. In. Out.
Come on, girls. In. Out.
Check oars.
The egg has been recovered.
You should be pleased.
I'm not pleased
it was stolen in the first place.
Nor that the thief
knows enough to bring it here.
He's obviously an adventurer
with possible blackmail on his mind.
Anyway, I have him as my guest
at the Monsoon Palace.
And he will tell us
all he knows very quickly.
- Who is he?
- Englishman.
Likes eggs. Preferably Fabergé.
And dice. Preferably loaded.
His name is James Bond.
Bring him here.
He's dangerous. After he's talked,
we must get rid of him immediately.
No.
A "no" from you
has little chance of becoming a "yes".
I assume, therefore,
that the meeting is over.
But you're making a serious mistake.
Well, so far I can't complain
about the valet service.
Dinner. 8 o'clock.
- Good evening, Mr Bond.
- Good evening.
Well rested?
I believe you and Miss Magda have met.
- It was a pleasure.
- You're too kind.
You don't mind if we start?
The soufflé can't wait.
At the risk of appearing
to be making light dinner conversation,
may I ask exactly why I am here?
I mean, after all, you do have the egg.
True. But we don't have all the answers.
Well, supposing, for argument's sake,
I don't feel like talking?
Don't worry, you will.
Let me guess.
Thumbscrews and hot coals.
Hardly. We're much more
sophisticated than that.
- Sodium Pentothal?
- A bit crude. Very unreliable.
We prefer curare with
an effective psychedelic compound.
Guaranteed results.
- But with permanent brain damage.
- An unfortunate side effect.
One of our specialities.
Stuffed sheep's head.
It's odd, but when I'm stared at
I seem to lose my appetite.
Oh, thank you for dinner.
Until tomorrow, then.
- Well, I'll say good night.
- I could come in for a nightcap.
Some other time, perhaps.
I don't suppose you'd care
for a nightcap? No.
I trust you had a pleasant flight.
If you step this way,
I think you will find everything is in order.
Congratulations on the quality of
your workmanship, Kamal Khan.
Thank you, General Orlov.
As you can see, each piece
has been meticulously duplicated
according to Lenkin's specifications.
Good. Have it put aboard the helicopter.
- Can they be trusted?
- I assure you oftheir silence.
We are both playing for enormous stakes.
I get what I want,
then you get the genuine jewellery.
Exactly...
The precise timing will be essential.
Remember: Nothing must be changed.
One week from today, in Karl-Marx-Stadt.
- Karl-Marx-Stadt.
- Correct.
- Everything taken care of?
- As you ordered, Excellence.
- So, you recovered it?
- From an accomplice ofthe thief.
He must be eliminated at once.
There must be no further security breach.
This fake has caused enough trouble.
I must go.
Everything has been most satisfactory.
Most kind, General Orlov.
Get Bond.
The Englishman has escaped.
He won't go very far. We'll track him.
Good.
Let the sport commence.
Head him off.
Sit!
We have him.
Go round. He's in there.
Hiss off.
Don't let him get away.
C'mom, buddy, c'mon.
- Hey, you all right, buddy?
- I'm fine.
- Are you with our group?
- No, ma'am. I'm with the economy tour.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org