Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Our man's in position
on the center camera.
It's like a terrorist supermarket.
Chinese Long March Scud,
Panther AS-565 attack helicopter...
...a pair of Russian mortars, and
the crates look like American rifles.
Chilean mines, German explosives.
Fun for the whole family.
IDs.
White Rook to White Knight.
Show us the pawns.
You see, he did get through, admiral.
Start with that chap in the middle.
Load the ID program, please.
Database ID search.
Checking the databases.
We've got our first match.
Satoshi Isagura.
Chemical expert.
Wanted for the Tokyo subway attack.
Currently working for
the insurgent force in Zaire.
Henry Gupta. American.
Practically invented
techno-terrorism.
Started out as a student radical
at Berkeley in the '60s.
Now he sells his politics for cash.
- Zoom in on that, can you?
- That looks like an American encoder.
They use it to control navigation
satellites: The GPS system.
Will the CIA be more upset
that they lost it or that we found it?
Excuse me. Admiral?
Thank you, M, we've seen enough.
This is now a military operation.
You saw the Gatling gun?
Are your troops prepared
for that kind of firepower?
We have election
in Moscow next week.
The president said any loss
of life is unacceptable.
We'll take the naval option.
In one strike, we take out
half the world's terrorists.
- Admiral Roebuck, I must protest.
- Get me the Chester,
- Let's not waste time.
- My man isn't finished.
Black King to White Bishop.
Authorization to fire.
Get your man out of there.
His job is over.
Weapons authorized,
Prepare to fire,
On my count.
Five, four, three, two, one.
Missile away.
Time to target:
Four minutes, eight seconds.
White Knight, four minutes to impact.
Get out of there.
Yes, damn it, I know what it is.
It's on the screen in front of me.
It's a jeep in front of a plane.
Now, get the hell out of there!
- What the hell's going on?
- You will not wait!
- That's an order!
- What is your man waiting for?
White Knight? Oh, my God!
Those are Soviet SB-5
nuclear torpedoes.
- lf the cruise hits them...
- Order them to abort the missile.
- H, M, S, Chester, urgent.
- White Knight, come in.
Abort missile. Abort missile.
- Abort missile.
Captain, sir, missile out of range.
Unable to destroy,
- White Knight...
- Alert NATO, the Pentagon.
- Will it trigger the torpedoes?
- It might.
But even if it does not,
there's enough plutonium...
...to make Chernobyl
look like picnic.
Bloody hell. Can't you people
keep anything locked up?
Evacuate your troops,
and get him out of there, now.
White Knight, come in.
- Keep trying, damn it.
- White Knight, come in.
Repeat, White Knight, come in.
Filthy habit.
I've got the encoder.
- What the hell is he doing?
- His job.
He's going for the bombs.
Get that jeep!
Get out of it, James.
One minute to impact.
Thirty seconds to impact.
Back-seat driver.
White Knight to White Rook.
I've evacuated the area,
Ask the admiral where
he'd like his bombs delivered,
Sound the general alarm.
The ship has been overflown
by two Chinese MiGs,
We believe they have hostile intent.
Hands to action stations,
Officer of the watch, maximum speed.
Come left 40 degrees.
Aye, aye, sir.
Revolutions 1-6-0, port 20.
Are they insane?
The Chinese pilot insists that
we are only 11 miles off their coast...
...and he will fire if we don't
turn around and go to a Chinese port.
Send this:
"We are in international waters...
...and will defend ourselves
if attacked.
Copy all this
to the Admiralty, urgent.
Are we absolutely sure
of our position?
Yes, sir. An exact satellite fix.
Captain, we are ready to launch.
Shut down the engines.
Maintain full silence.
A stealth ship may be invisible
to radar but the sea drill isn't.
We'll launch next time
the MiGs fly by...
...and the British will think
it's a Chinese aerial torpedo.
I should report in.
Stamper to Hamburg,
Phase one is in progress,
I'll report back to you
with an update,
- The MiGs are making another pass.
- Let's start the show.
Sea drill in position.
Start the drill.
- Release it.
- Sea drill away.
Green 3-0,
torpedo, torpedo, torpedo.
Green 3-0, center bearing 1-1-4.
Officer of the Watch,
come hard right, 1-4-1.
There's been no sonar contact, sir.
The MiGs must have dropped it.
Bearing steady. It's gonna hit, sir.
Brace, brace, brace.
- Target: 1200.
- Knock, knock.
Let's go upstairs.
- Turn left.
- Rotating 90 degrees.
Now they're wondering why
the torpedo hasn't exploded.
PWO, captain.
Full damage report.
Backup power, immediately!
Switch to alternate supply.
Three generators are down, sir.
Flooding on four deck aft.
Sir, we're now down
14 degrees by the stern.
Yeoman, send to Admiralty:
"Have been torpedoed by
Chinese MiGs. Sinking."
Give them our position.
Right. Abandon ship.
Abandon ship!
Everyone on deck! Come on!
One missile at the MiGs.
Maintaining radio silence.
Their last broadcast, sir.
Mr. Gupta's little trick
with the encoder worked.
They gave their final position
70 miles from here.
The British Navy
will never find them.
Survivors in the water.
Mr. Stamper,
I'm having fun with my headlines.
I need to know
the exact number of survivors.
Now, I'm late for a meeting. Make sure
you use the right kind of ammunition.
Yes, sir,
Delicious.
Start the recovery operation.
Send our divers
down to the Devonshire,
Mr, Gupta? Phase one is complete,
Good morning, my golden retrievers.
What kind of havoc shall the Carver
Media Group create in the world today?
- News.
- Floods in Pakistan, riots in Paris,
- And a plane crash in California,
- Excellent.
Mr. Jones, are we ready
to release our new software?
Yes, sir,
As requested, it's full of bugs,,,
,,, which means people will be
forced to upgrade for years,
Outstanding.
Mr. Wallace, call the president.
Tell him if he doesn't sign the bill
lowering the cable rates...
...we'll release a video of him
with the cheerleader...
...in the Chicago motel room.
- Inspired, sir,
After he signs the bill,
release the tape anyway.
Consider him slimed,
Excuse me.
- He's on transponder seven.
- Mr. Stamper?
Phase two is underway,
I have the videotape,
I haven't seen it myself,
but I'm told the footage is excellent,
Plus, there were 17 survivors
for your headlines,
Good work, Stamper.
- Thank you.
- Don't mention it.
Make sure you keep it
in a safe place.
Gentlemen and ladies...
...hold the presses.
This just in.
By a curious quirk of fate,
we have the perfect story...
...with which to launch our
Satellite News Network tonight.
It seems a small crisis is brewing
in the South China Seas.
I want full newspaper coverage.
I want magazine stories.
I want books. I want films.
I want TV. I want radio.
I want us on the air
24 hours a day.
This is our moment!
And a billion people
around this planet...
...will watch it, hear it...
...and read about it
from the Carver Media Group.
There's no news like bad news.
How do you say
"I'm not here" in Danish?
Just ignore it.
Those are words they just
don't have in their vocabulary.
- Bond here.
- Go to a secure line, 007,
Going to scrambler, channel four.
That's ridiculous.
That ship was in international waters.
- We can't be certain.
- James? Where are you?
Oh, Moneypenny.
I'm just up here at Oxford
brushing up on a little Danish.
Little?
I'm afraid you're gonna have to
kiss off your lesson,
We've got a situation here
at the Ministry of Defense.
We're sending the fleet to China.
I'll be there in an hour.
Make that 30 minutes.
You always were
a cunning linguist, James.
- Don't ask.
- Don't tell.
That's preposterous. We know exactly
where that ship was positioned.
The GPS system... Global
Positioning Satellites do not lie.
Yes, but our Singapore station
picked up a mysterious signal...
...on the GPS frequency
at the time of the attack.
It could've sent that ship
off course.
- I have a missing British frigate...
- I'm aware of that!
And instead of decisive action,
all you wanna do is investigate.
My goal is to prevent World War III,
admiral, and I don't think...
...sending an armada into the recovery
area is the best way to do it.
Where, exactly, did this mysterious
GPS signal come from?
- We're still investigating.
- "Investigating."
M, sometimes I don't think
you have the balls for this job.
Perhaps, but the advantage is...
...I don't have to think
with them all the time.
That's enough.
Now, where do we stand?
It was an unprovoked attack
on a ship in international waters.
We send in the fleet for recovery
and prepare for full retaliation.
Moderation. We investigate...
...and stop short of sending
the entire British Navy...
...within 10 minutes
of the world's largest air force.
- When will our ships be in position?
- Forty-eight hours.
Christ!
The press are already
screaming for blood.
The last thing we want to do
is escalate the situation.
I'm afraid it may be too late
to worry about that.
Seventeen British sailors murdered!
"According to Vietnamese officials
who recovered the bodies...
...the victims were riddled
with the same ammunition...
...used by the Chinese Air Force.
- Did you leak this?
No.
- It's the first I've heard of it.
- Well, this settles it.
We send in the fleet.
M, you have 48 hours to investigate.
There is one strange thing.
When I called our contact
in Saigon, he said the Vietnamese...
...only found our sailors
three hours ago.
How'd they get the paper out
so fast?
Somebody at Tomorrow knew before
the Vietnamese government did.
How much do you know
about Elliot Carver, 007?
Worldwide media baron.
Able to topple governments
with a single broadcast.
Carver owns
that newspaper Tomorrow,
I didn't want to discuss it
in front of the minister...
...but that mysterious signal came
from one of Carver's satellites.
The PM would have my head
if he knew you were investigating him.
I'm sending you to Hamburg, 007.
We've arranged for your invitation...
...to a party
at Carver's Media center.
They're celebrating the launch
of a new satellite...
...because now he has the ability
to reach every human on the Earth.
Except the Chinese,
who have refused broadcast rights.
James, your ticket, cover story
and rental car reservation.
Sign here, please.
I believe you once had a relationship
with Carver's wife, Paris.
That was a long time ago, M...
...before she was married.
I didn't realize
it was public knowledge.
Queen and country, James.
Your job is to find out whether Carver
or someone in his organization...
...sent that ship off course
and why.
Use your relationship
with Mrs. Carver if necessary.
I doubt if she'll remember me.
Remind her.
Then pump her for information.
You'll just have to decide
how much pumping is needed, James.
If only that were true
of you and I, Moneypenny.
If you'll just sign here, Mr. Bond.
It's the insurance damage waiver...
...for your beautiful new car.
- Will you need collision coverage?
- Yes.
Fire?
Probably.
- Property destruction?
- Definitely.
Personal injury?
I hope not, but accidents do happen.
They frequently do with you.
Well, that takes care
of the normal wear and tear.
Do I need any other protection?
Only from me, 007, unless you bring
that car back in pristine order.
- Shall we?
Your new BMW 750.
All the usual refinements.
Machine guns, rockets...
...the GPS tracking system.
Welcome, Please fasten seat belt and
obey all instructions for a safe trip,
I thought you'd pay more attention
to a female voice.
- I think we've met.
- I am not interested...
...in your sordid escapades.
Let's get on with it, shall we?
Your new telephone.
Talk here, listen here.
So that's what I've been
doing wrong all these years.
It also includes
a fingerprint scanner...
...and a 20,000-volt
security system.
And this I'm particularly proud of:
The remote control for your car.
Tap twice.
One, two.
Now, draw your finger...
...very slowly across the pad...
...to drive the car.
It's surprisingly difficult to drive,
but with practice...
Well, let's see how she responds
to my touch, eh, Q?
I think we understand each other.
Grow up, 007.
Attention, Engine running,
Please shut door now,
Anyway, there's absolutely no truth
in this malicious rumor...
...that I started running
Mad Cow Disease stories...
...simply because Sir Angus Black,
the great British beef baron...
...lost 10,000 pounds to me in a game
of poker and refused to pay up.
Moreover, there's even
less truth in the rumor...
...that I took 100 million francs
from the French...
...to keep the stories running
for another year.
- Excuse me, Mr. Carver.
- Yes.
This is the new banker, Mr?
Bond. James Bond.
Another new banker.
I seem to collect them.
Tell me, Mr. Bond...
...how's the market reacting
to the crisis?
Well, currencies are off.
Your stock is soaring.
I don't believe we have met.
- Elliot Carver.
- Wai Lin.
I'm from the
New China News Agency.
I don't recall seeing your name
on the guest list.
I have a confession.
It's not. I snuck in.
Why would you do that, my dear?
I wanted to meet you.
Outstanding.
I admire a woman
who takes the initiative.
You should work in
my Beijing bureau.
Mr. Carver.
- You don't have a bureau in Beijing.
- Call me Elliot.
I always wondered how I'd feel
if I ever saw you again.
Now I know.
Was it something I said?
How about the words
"I'll be right back"?
- Something came up.
- Something always came up.
- And how are you, Paris?
- Much better now. We're even.
Something to drink, Mrs. Carver?
Mr. Bond will have a vodka martini,
shaken not stirred.
Mrs. Carver will have a tequila,
straight shot.
No, Mrs. Carver will have a glass
of Mr. Carver's champagne.
I see you've moved up
in the world, Paris.
And tonight, you're a banker.
I saw the guest list.
Tell me, James, do you still sleep
with a gun under your pillow?
- To you.
- No, to the gun.
So I take it this isn't a social visit?
Your husband may be in trouble.
The emperor of the air.
If you think you're going after him,
you're the one who's in trouble.
Perhaps, but it's either him
or someone in his organization.
I see. And you figured you could
charm the dirt out of me.
No. That wasn't my plan.
Good. Because if it
comes to a choice...
...between you and Elliot,
I've made my bed.
You don't sleep in it anymore.
There you are.
Darling.
I've been looking
everywhere for you.
I want you to meet Wai Lin,
New China News Agency.
- Hello, Mrs. Carver.
- It's a pleasure.
And this is James Bond.
I didn't realize you knew each other.
- We're old friends.
- Casual acquaintances.
He dated my roommate in Zurich.
I'm thinking of getting Wai Lin
behind a news desk.
That's wonderful.
I'm sure she won't resist...
...too much.
Tell me, Elliot, I was just
wondering about your satellites...
...the way you've positioned
yourself globally.
They're merely tools
for information, Mr. Bond.
Or disinformation.
Say, if you wanted to manipulate
the course of governments or people.
Or even a ship.
That's very interesting, Mr. Bond.
You have a vivid imagination
for a banker.
Perhaps I should commission you
to write a novel.
Oh, heavens, no.
I'd be lost at sea. Adrift.
Mr. Carver?
It's time to begin the festivities.
Excuse me. Darling?
So how do you really know him?
I told you, he's a banker.
I met him in Zurich.
You're a terrible liar, dear.
I have a problem with a banker.
Could I see you a moment?
Ladies and gentlemen.
Mr. Carver's broadcast will begin
in 10 minutes in the main studio.
Exactly what kind of banking
do you specialize in, Mr. Bond?
Hostile takeovers. Shall we?
Carver must feel at home
in a room like this.
It's nice to talk to the world.
Looks like there's someone
who wants to talk to you.
Mr. Bond, you have
an urgent phone call.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are live in five...
...four, three, two...
Good evening.
Tonight's broadcast was supposed
to be a celebration...
...marking the completion of
the Carver Global Satellite Network.
But, as you're well aware...
...a terrible conflict looms tonight
in the South China Sea...
...which, unchecked...
...has the potential to destroy
every human being on Earth.
- I want to assure my viewers that I,,,
- This way, please.
,,, Elliot Carver, have spoken
with the prime minister in London,,,
,,, and the chairman in Beijing,,,
,,, and have offered my services
as an impartial...
It's a soundproof room, Mr. Bond.
Nobody hears you scream.
Herr Stamper,
we have made contact.
Make him uncomfortable.
I'll be there in a few moments.
- with its printing presses
that run 24 hours a day...
...and its satellite facilities
linking every last...
You seem very concerned
about Mr. Carver's business.
He wants to know why.
Why did I do it, you ask,
The answer is simple: power,
The power to illuminate
the far corners of the globe,
Not for higher profits,,,
...but for higher understanding between
the people of this great planet.
Put him in the chair. Maybe we play
a little number on his head.
And what do I expect in return?
Worldwide domination.
Complete, utter, total
worldwide domination,
But not over governments or ideology,
Over tyranny and isolation
and ignorance,
The Carver Media Group Network
has the ability,,,
,,, to reach every person
in every village in every nation,
But do not fear me,,,
,,, for tonight I offer you
my declaration of principles:
A promise to the men and women
of this planet,,,
,,, my brothers and sisters
whom I so humbly serve,
I promise to report the news
without fear or favor,
I promise to be a force
for good in this world,
Fighting injustice,
crushing intolerance,,,
,,, battling inhumanity,
- Striking a blow for freedom,
- It's time for...
...a station break.
- What's happening?
- We've lost power.
- We're off the air.
- What?!
Ladies and gentlemen, stay calm.
There's no need to go for the exit.
We will go on in a few minutes' time.
What do you mean, you don't know?
You're fired! Get out of my sight!
And, in a rather embarrassing note,,,
,,, scrappy media mogul Elliot Carver
was cut off the air tonight,,,
,,, in mid-speech during
the inaugural broadcast,,,
,,, of his Worldwide Satellite Network,
Sorry, Elliot,
but we didn't do it,
Glorious evening, wasn't it?
Come on, Elliot.
Ignore those people.
- Sometimes these things happen.
- Not to me.
Not to me!
When I was 16, I went to work
for a newspaper in Hong Kong.
It was a rag, but the editor
taught me one important lesson.
The key to a great story
is not who...
...or what or when...
...but why.
Your friend, Mr. Bond,
made a mess tonight.
- I want to know why.
- I told you, I barely know him.
Barely?
I was curious
who Carver would send.
He's on to you.
Well, we know where you stand.
You made your bed.
I'm standing in your doorway.
Then turn around and go home.
You can tell him you didn't
get anything out of me.
That's it? Go home?
I didn't ask you
to get involved in this.
It's too late for that.
Why did you marry him?
He told me he loved me.
That always sounds good.
Do you know I used to look in
the papers for your obituary?
Well, I'm sorry
I keep disappointing you.
What was it, James?
Did I get too close?
Did I get too close for comfort?
Yes.
I missed you.
What did you find?
I hacked into the mainframe
at the bank.
They're using
an SSL2 encryption, 128...
Spare me the technobabble, please.
Bond's got a perfect
employment record. Ten years.
He's crossed every T,
he's dotted every I.
- Which means?
- Government agent.
I call it
Gupta's Law of Creative Anomalies.
If it sounds too good to be true,
it always is.
Do you think my wife knows?
There's a lot of garbage, but
if you dial down the ambient noise...
Tell me, James, do you still sleep
with a gun under your pillow?
Play it again.
Tell me, James, do you still sleep
with a gun under your pillow?
I think we should set an appointment
for my wife with the doctor.
Tell me, James, do you still sleep
with a gun under your pillow?
- I have to go.
- No, you don't.
I can get you out of the country
in four hours.
I have no choice.
No one can protect me
from him, not even you.
- You do have a choice.
- Only if you let him go.
I can't do that.
He has a secret lab on the top floor
even I'm not supposed to know about.
There's an emergency hatch
on the roof.
- You don't have to do this.
- It's the easiest way to get in.
Don't argue with me, James.
You know...
...this job of yours...
...it's murder on relationships.
Until I get back next week,
I want two guards...
...outside this office
24 hours a day.
Nobody gets in. Got it?
We'll take care of it.
What do we do with the satellite?
Send this thing to the launch site.
And be careful.
It's worth $300 million. You break it,
you bought it. Understand?
I hate traveling.
I never know what to pack.
Looking for a news story?
They'll print anything these days.
Yes?
Good morning, Mr, Bond,
Elliot Carver,
I believe you've got
two items that belong to me,
What are you talking about?
The red box, Mr, Bond,,,
,,, and my wife in your hotel room,
He's coming.
Fingerprint ID accepted,
Please select security system level,
Tell me if you find the encoder.
- Call me immediately,
- Yeah,
And in breaking news,,,
,,, it is with great sadness that we
announce the death of Paris Carver,,,
,,, who has become an international
figure since she became the wife,,,
,,, of Elliot Carver,
chairman of this network,
According to police officials
in Hamburg, Germany,,,
,,, Mrs, Carver was found dead
this morning,,,
,,, in a hotel suite in that city
in unusual circumstances,,,
,,, on which police
have refused to elaborate,
A coroner has been called for
and is expected to deliver,,,
,,, his full report within
the next three days,
Her body was discovered along with
the body of an unidentified man,,,
,,, who appeared to be the victim
of a self-inflicted gun wound,
Reached aboard his private jet
en route...
I have a clear shot at your head,
Mr. Bond.
Stand up, slowly.
Drop your gun and
kick it toward me, ja?
At present, police
have refused to speculate,,,
,,, on a motive in this
murder-suicide,
Good. Now...
...lie down on the bed
next to Mrs. Carver.
We extend our deepest sympathies
to Mr, Carver,
This story will be
on the news in an hour.
- Tomorrow's news today.
- Just so.
My name is Dr. Kaufman.
I am an outstanding
pistol marksman.
Take my word for it, ja?
Get the sledgehammers.
She struggled terribly, Mr. Bond.
It's a pity you got her
involved in all this.
It won't look like a suicide
if you shoot me from over there.
I am a professor
of forensic medicine.
Believe me, Mr. Bond,
I could shoot you from Stuttgart...
...and still create the proper effect.
My art is in great demand,
Mr. Bond.
I go all over the world.
I am especially good
at the celebrity overdose.
But now, I'm afraid, Mr. Bond,
that our little...
Stamper! Stop yelling in my ear, ja?
Sir, they can't get into the car.
You can't be serious.
- Did you call the Auto Club?
- Do you wanna call them?
Make him tell you how to open it,
Okay, I ask.
This is very embarrassing.
It seems there is
a red box in your car.
They can't get to it.
They want me
to make you unlock the car.
I feel like an idiot.
I don't know what to say.
I am to torture you
if you don't do it.
- You have a doctorate in that too?
- No, no, no.
This is more like a hobby.
But I'm very gifted.
Oh, I believe you.
- My cell phone opens the car.
- No, Mr. Bond.
I do it, ja?
Recall, three, send.
Wait.
I'm just a professional doing a job.
Me too.
Dr. Kaufman.
Welcome, Please fasten seat belt,
Reduce speed,
Pedestrians in roadway,
Driver alert,
Obstruction ahead,
Reduce speed now,
Reminder:
Unsafe driving will void warranty,
Congratulations on a safe journey,
Yo! Jimbo!
Wade, what are you doing here?
You know the world's my office.
Let's go this way.
Did Q bring you up to speed?
Yeah. I brought along
the GPS calibration unit.
By the way, officially Uncle Sam
is neutral in this turkey shoot.
And unofficially?
We have no interest in seeing
World War III, unless we start it.
Dr. Greenwalt.
He's the Air Force GPS expert.
Sorry about all this security...
...but the GPS encoder is one of
the most closely guarded secrets...
...in the U.S. military.
Show him what you got.
Jesus, it's the missing encoder.
How the hell did you get that?
Picked it up in Hamburg
yesterday morning.
Could somebody use this
to send a ship off course?
- Like the Devonshire?
- Whoa!
I didn't hear anybody mention
the Devonshire, Did you?
- No.
- Good. So just answer his question.
Well, in theory, if you could alter
the timing chip...
...you could slowly
send a ship off course.
Like putting a magnet
near a compass.
Yeah, exactly.
- Then check this out.
- Oh, yeah.
Those two circles should be
lining up on top of each other.
Somebody's tampered
with your encoder.
If we knew the last time and position
the Devonshire thought she was...
...could you figure out
exactly where she sank?
Sure.
- Wade?
- Yeah?
I have a small favor to ask.
The high-altitude,
low-opening jump, the HALO jump...
...is where we get the most fatalities,
so listen up.
You free-fall for 5 miles and use your
oxygen, or you'll die of asphyxiation.
Sounds like my first marriage.
Next, after the free-fall...
...pop the chute at 200 feet,
below the Chinese radar.
You'll be traveling
at over 200 miles an hour.
This snaps your head back
like a cantaloupe.
Don't crack your skull open
on the tanks.
I'll keep that in mind.
One last thing: When you hit the water,
don't forget to cut away your chute.
Ninety percent of people
killed in HALO jumps...
...got tangled up in their chutes
and drowned. Got it?
Seems like a lot
just to save the world.
I've got no choice.
I have to prove that ship
was deliberately sent off course.
- One minute!
- Is the pickup set?
You bet. After your mission,
turn on your beacon.
The extraction team
will pick you up after dark.
Buddha bless!
- I just noticed something.
- Yeah?
This is where the ship
thought it was.
This is where it really is.
But see that island?
- Yeah.
- That means where he's jumping...
...between the British
and Chinese fleets...
Technically they're not
in Chinese territorial waters.
- They belong to Vietnam.
- Vietnam?
Does he have any
U.S. government markings on him?
The parachute,
the wet suit, the fins.
If the Vietnamese catch him,
they're gonna go crazy.
He didn't even say goodbye.
Still interested in hostile takeovers?
It's the opportunities for travel
that I like best about banking.
Get them out of the water.
If I didn't know better, I'd say you
were following me around, Mr. Bond.
You'll have to admit, though...
...we seem to have developed
a certain attachment to each other.
Hopefully not for long.
Another Carver building.
If I didn't know better, I'd say
he'd developed an edifice complex.
General Chang?
Friend of yours?
Mr. Bond. Miss Lin.
Welcome to Saigon.
It's always nice to see you, Elliot.
I hadn't intended opening
this center until tomorrow...
...but as you're here you can help me
write the inaugural story:
Your obituaries.
I hope you extended
the same courtesy to Paris.
Actually, Mr. Bond, you're the one
who wrote my late wife's obituary...
...when you asked her to betray me.
Still, let's see.
"British secret service agent
James Bond...
...and his collaborator Wai Lin...
...of the Chinese People's
External Security Force...
...were found...
...dead this morning...
...in Vietnam.
Lacks punch, don't you think?
It's old news, Elliot.
We've been working together
for months.
Both our governments know what you
and General Chang are up to.
I don't think so.
You may have seen the general
in the hallway just now...
...but perhaps,
with all your jetting around...
...you've not had chance to peruse
today's headlines.
I rather like the last one.
It isn't even mine.
I never believe what I read
in the press anyway.
Therein lies your problem, Mr. Bond.
You see, we're both men of action,
but your era and Miss Lin's is passing.
Words are the new weapons,
satellites the new artillery.
And you become the new
supreme allied commander?
Exactly!
Caesar had his legions,
Napoleon had his armies...
...I have my divisions.
TV, news, magazines.
And by midnight I'll have reached
and influenced more people...
...than anyone in the history
of this planet, save God Himself.
And the best he ever managed
was the Sermon on the Mount.
You really are quite insane.
The distance
between insanity and genius...
...is measured only by success.
Excuse me.
- General Chang is waiting.
- lf you'll forgive me...
Your appearance here has forced me
to move up my timetable slightly.
I'll leave you in the capable hands
of Mr. Stamper and his toys.
Perhaps you'd like to see them.
- Sir. The helicopter.
- Thanks, Gupta.
Mr. Stamper is a protg
of the late Dr. Kaufman...
...who was schooling him in
the ancient art of chakra torture.
He was like a father to me.
Really? Interesting role model.
According to Eastern philosophy,
the body has seven chakra points.
Energy centers,
like the heart or genitals.
The purpose of these implements
is to probe those organs...
...inflicting the maximum amount
of pain...
...whilst keeping the victim alive
for as long as possible.
Dr. Kaufman's record
was 52 hours.
I'm hoping to break it.
I would've thought watching
your TV shows was torture enough.
Save this one till last.
When you remove Mr. Bond's heart...
...there should just be enough time
for him to watch it stop beating.
Excuse me.
Go! Go! Go! Go!
We can use the banner.
Hope it holds.
- Get after them!
- Ready? Go!
Next time I'll take the elevator.
Push! Push!
- Get a car!
- No, no!
- Yes, a car!
- A bike is quicker.
The keys.
Someone always forgets them.
What are you doing?
I'm driving. Get off.
Get on the back.
I'm slipping.
Stop fidgeting back there.
What are you...?
Give me that.
Clutch! Clutch! Clutch!
- Turn right.
- No, left.
Who's driving? Come on!
Clutch!
Left! Left!
How many back there?
I can't see. Hold on.
What are you...? What?
- Don't get any ideas.
- I'd never dream of it.
One. No, two.
- Go for the barrels.
- What?
Very good.
Hold on!
Let's take the highway.
- Helicopter!
- All right, keep your shirt on.
- Get on the back of the bike.
- Are you trying to protect me?
No. I need to balance the bike.
Get on the back.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
Go!
Pop the clutch.
- It's behind us.
- Move!
Get out of the way!
You see the chopper?
I can't see. Hold on.
What are you...?
Trapped.
Never.
Would you pass the soap?
Over there.
You were pretty good
with that hook.
It comes from growing up
in a rough neighborhood.
You were pretty good
on the bike.
Well, that comes from
not growing up at all.
Here. Allow me.
Don't get any ideas, Mr. Bond.
Just off the cuff,
I thought we might link up.
Work hand in hand?
Stick closer to each other.
Maybe we go after
General Chang together.
Your turn.
Thanks for washing my hair.
I work alone.
Lucky for you I stopped by.
I could've taken care of him.
But you didn't.
Give me the earring.
Copy of a Makarov 59.
Standard issue, Chinese army.
Looks like General Chang
wants you dead.
You still think
you can do this alone?
It depends whether your mission
is peace or revenge.
This is about stopping a war.
Last year we found
stealth material was missing...
...from one of
General Chang's bases.
I followed a lead
to Carver's headquarters in Hamburg.
Stealth material?
We thought he was building
a stealth plane.
No. Stealth boat.
That's the only way they could
get close to the Devonshire,,,
...so they could drill inside
the missile room.
Remember? They stole
a cruise missile from that ship.
He said he was moving the timetable
forward to midnight.
Yes, of course he did.
Under cover of darkness
he'll position the stealth boat...
...near the British fleet...
...fire the missile into China.
- And we will retaliate.
- And Carver will provide the pictures.
- I have to warn Beijing.
- No.
Let's warn both our governments,
get them talking.
It'll give us time to find the boat.
Stand up.
It's just like home.
You get the equipment,
I'll send the messages.
On second thought, you type.
First we have to find the boat.
Of all the harbors and inlets
controlled by General Chang...
...22 are in
highly populated areas.
That leaves 14
where he could hide a stealth boat.
You can see it during the day.
It's invisible to radar,
but not the human eye.
Very novel.
He'd have to hide it
someplace where...
...he could sail to the Devonshire
and back in one night.
This looks familiar.
- We've made some improvements.
- Have you, indeed?
Okay. Four hours out
and four hours back.
Assume the boat is traveling
at a speed of 30 knots.
I've always been a fan
of Chinese technology.
According to this...
...there are four places
where he could harbor the boat.
Up on your left.
Run a cross-check on those areas
for anything suspicious.
Ah, the new Walther.
I asked Q to get me one of these.
I've got it. Look.
Four missing boats.
Three unexplained drownings.
That has to be it.
Ha Long Bay.
He knows the island.
He says that it's dangerous for
boats to be around there at sunset...
...but for 5000 American dollars...
...he'll take us.
- Good.
Maybe he'll take a check.
It's mostly dull routine,
of course...
...but every now and then you get to
sail on a beautiful evening like this...
...and sometimes work with a decadent
agent of a corrupt Western power.
And they say Communists
don't know how to have fun.
I hate to disappoint you...
...but I don't even have
a little red book.
If anything happens to me...
...the fuses for the mines
are in here.
We're gonna finish this together.
And if I may say so,
you found the right...
...decadent, corrupt Western agent...
...as a partner.
- See the stealth?
- No.
It's getting late
and this is the last cove in the bay.
Yeah, that's it.
Set the timers for 10 minutes.
That'll give us time to get out of
here before the ship explodes.
Even if it doesn't sink,
it'll show up on radar.
- Our fleets will finish the job.
- lf they got our message.
- Okay, you, up and over.
- Okay.
We're in position
between the fleets,
Fire one missile
at the flagship of each fleet.
The Chinese will think the British
are rattling the saber...
...the British will think the Chinese
are being belligerent...
...and the media will provide
cool, objective coverage.
Let the mayhem begin.
Missile lock-on.
Send a signal to the Admiralty:
"Task group under missile attack."
Sir, AWACS reports two waves
of land-based MiG 21 s inbound.
The first group should be
on our screens in two minutes.
How long before the MiGs are within
firing range of the British fleet?
Twelve minutes.
What the hell do I pay you for?
If she's there, Bond is there.
Stamper, find them.
Wai Lin! Wai Lin! Camera!
If she blinks, kill her.
You come with me.
Stamper to Bridge, Bond is dead,
Delicious.
Make sure you clear all the mines,
and bring the girl up to me.
Are you sure you want her up here?
It's my business, Mr. Gupta.
I like an audience.
Ah, Miss Lin.
Your countrymen are being
so cooperative...
...so predictably eager
to save face.
My government knows you're
out here. They're looking for you.
Not according to our radar...
...where it seems your MiGs are
about to attack the British fleet...
...in how many minutes?
Nine minutes to firing range.
And even if they were
looking for me...
...we're on a stealth boat.
They can't see me, or you...
...or even your friend...
...the late Commander Bond...
...who is at this moment on his way
to the bottom of the South China Sea.
He's my new anchorman.
Pathetic.
What on earth's going on?
A message from 007...
...just confirmed by
my opposite number in China.
"Tell the fleet to search for a ship
that's almost invisible to radar."
The Chinese aren't the enemy.
Carver's been playing
both sides for fools.
Admiral, sir,
urgent message from the Admiralty.
Look at this.
Anything on radar that looks small?
Lifeboat, periscope, anything?
- No, sir.
- Stealth boat, sir? They've gone mad.
What you're about to witness, Miss
Lin, is not so much a missile attack...
...but the launch
of a new world order.
In five minutes, after your countrymen
have attacked the British fleet...
I shall retaliate
for dear old England...
...by sending this missile
into Beijing...
...where General Chang has just
called an emergency meeting...
...of the Chinese high command.
Unfortunately...
...General Chang
will be delayed in traffic...
...arriving just after the missile
has killed your leaders...
...and too late to stop the air force
from sinking the entire British fleet.
But he'll be just in time to take over
the government, negotiate a truce...
...and emerge as a world leader...
...with the Nobel Peace Prize.
- And what do you get?
- Me?
Oh, nothing.
Just exclusive broadcasting rights
in China for the next hundred years.
Ready to rock and ruin.
If you'll excuse me, my dear,
I have a deadline to meet.
Prepare for the missile launch.
Mr. Gupta.
Hello, Elliot.
Interesting plan.
But I think I have
something that belongs to you,
So much for German efficiency.
Mr. Stamper.
- Don't shoot him yet.
- Hold your fire.
Welcome to my world crisis,
Mr. Bond.
Even trade, Elliot.
Gupta for Wai Lin.
You can't fire the missile
without him.
And it seems you can't resist
any woman in my possession.
What are you waiting for?
Shoot him!
I told you we're going to
finish this together.
How romantic.
Do you realize
how absurd your position is?
No more absurd than
starting a war for ratings.
Great men have always manipulated
the media to save the world.
Look at William Randolph Hearst,
who told his photographers:
"You provide the pictures,
I'll provide the war."
I've just taken it one step further.
Sorry about that.
I tuned out there
for a moment, Elliot.
Touch.
Mr. Gupta...
...is the missile ready to fire?
Press the magic button,
Beijing disappears.
Then it seems
you've outlived your contract.
You see, Mr. Bond,
I have a backup plan.
So do I.
He's breached the hull.
They'll see us on radar.
Sir, we have a small,
intermittent contact on the surface.
Plot the bearing 1-1-2 degrees.
It's a very weak signal, but I'd swear
it wasn't there a second ago, sir.
Yeoman, tell all ships not to fire on the
Chinese for any reason whatsoever.
Send the message
to the Chinese fleet commander:
"Have sighted unknown ship..."
Get those fires out!
Get down there
and protect the missile.
Oh, and Mr. Stamper,
would you please kill those bastards?
Nice work.
They're speeding up.
- We have to stop the boat.
- Can you take care of the engine room?
- Of course.
- Good. Do it and get off the ship.
I'm going to stop the missile.
Signal from
the Chinese fleet commander.
"To Royal Navy Task Group:
We also have the unknown ship
on our screens.
We will not fire
unless it turns towards China.
Until then, she's yours.
Good hunting."
Now, captain, whatever
the hell that thing is, sink it.
Right, sir. Is that echo
too weak for missile lock?
- Yes, sir.
- Right.
We'll do it the old-fashioned way.
Bond turned us into the target.
Along with himself.
Take evasive action.
Prepare the missile countdown
immediately.
Initializing launch sequence.
T minus five minutes and counting.
T minus five minutes and counting,
Sir, they're making 48 knots.
They'll be out of range
in two minutes.
Keep firing. Slow them down.
The engines are out. We're sitting
ducks here. Engine room.
Follow me!
T minus four minutes and counting,
Well done.
Officer watch, increase max.
Keep firing!
All hands, abandon ship.
Abandon ship.
Abandon ship, Abandon ship,
Mr. Stamper,
what are you doing about the girl?
Perhaps you'd consider
looking in the engine room.
T minus three minutes and counting,
You're too late again, Mr. Bond.
It's a bad habit of yours.
There's nothing you can do.
T minus two minutes and counting,
The missile's fully programmed.
It can't be stopped.
In minutes my plan will succeed.
And thanks largely to your efforts...
...the British Navy
will destroy the evidence...
...and I'll be out of here
in a Carver news helicopter...
...covering the event.
It's going to be a fantastic show.
I may have some breaking news
for you, Elliot.
You forgot the first rule
of mass media, Elliot:
Give the people what they want.
T minus one minute and counting,
Drop it, Mr. Bond...
...or I drop your friend.
It's over, Stamper.
Let her go.
Not between you and me.
James, try the detonators.
The missile will set them off.
Never argue with a woman.
They're always right.
T minus 40 seconds,
For Carver!
And Kaufman!
I owe you an unpleasant death,
Mr. Bond.
T minus 20 seconds,
We die together, Mr. Bond.
T minus 10 seconds,
Three,,,
,,, two, one,
M, Bedford reports
Carver went down with the ship.
Seems that Bond made it.
Moneypenny, take this release.
Elliot Carver is missing,
presumed drowned...
...while on a cruise aboard his
luxury yacht in the South China Sea.
At present
the local authorities believe...
...the media mogul
committed suicide.
Commander Bond,,,
,,, Colonel Lin,,,
,,, this is the H.M.S. Bedford.
Are you there?
They're looking for us, James.
Let's stay undercover.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org